Yongming Fan



fan322@purdue.edu

http://www.yongming.fan

Research Interest

My research interests lie at the intersection of applied cryptography, zero knowledge proof, protocol security evaluation, privacy, and software security. Specifically, I am intrigued by the potential of zk-SNARKs to enhance privacy and efficiency in various applications. I also have a keen interest in evaluating the security of cryptographic protocols software implementation, ensuring they are robust against emerging threats and vulnerabilities. Overall, my research aims to bridge the gap between theoretical cryptography and practical security solutions, addressing critical challenges in the rapidly evolving digital landscape.

Education

2020	_	Pres	eni
2020	_	LIES	=111

Ph.D. Computer Science Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

Advisor: Christina Garman

2018 - 2020

M.S. Computer Science, Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN Advisor: David Crandall

Thesis title: Segmentation of Retinal Optic from a New Approach Hough Transform

2014 - 2018

B.A. Mathematics, Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

B.S. Computer Science, Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Research Experience

Aug 2020 - Present

Research Assistant Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Visiting Scholar York University, Toronto, ON

Aug 2018 - Jul 2020

Research Assistant Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Jan 2017 - May 2017

Undergraduate Researcher Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Professional Service

Conference Leadership/Organization

2024

Organizer, NDSS Workshop on AI System with Confidential Computing

Program Committees

Reviewer, IEEE/ACM Transactions on Computational Biology and Bioinformatics

Reviewer, ICLR Workshop on Backdoor Attacks and Defenses in Machine Learning

Sub-Reviewer, IEEE International Conference on Medical Artificial Intelligence

2022

Sub-Reviewer, Financial Cryptography and Data Security

Research Publications

Publications



Yongming Fan, Yuquan Xu, and Christina Garman, "Snarkprobe: An automated security analysis framework for zksnark implementations," in International Conference on Applied Cryptography and Network Security, Springer, 2024.

- Xurui Li, Yue Qin, Rui Zhu, Tianqianjin Lin, **Yongming Fan**, Yangyang Kang, Kaisong Song, Fubang Zhao, Changlong Sun, Haixu Tang, and Xiaozhong Liu, "Semi-supervised semantic-topological iteration network for financial risk detection via news label diffusion," in *Proceedings of the 2023 Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing*, 2023.
- Yongming Fan, "Segmentation of retinal optic from a new approach hough transform," M.S. thesis, Indiana University Bloomington, May 2020.

Submitted

- Yongming Fan, Priyam Biswas, and Christina Garman, "Sok: A systematic study of cryptographic function identification approaches in binaries," Currently under review, 2023.
- Yongming Fan and Christina Garman, "Sigmagraph: Using graph algorithms to verify sigma protocols," Currently under review, 2023.
- Zhixin Li, Rui Zhu, Zihao Wang, Jiale Li, Kaiyuan Liu, Yue Qin, **Yongming Fan**, Mingyu Gu, Zhihui Lu, Jie Wu, Hongfeng Chai, Xiaofeng Wang, and Haixu Tang, "Fairfix: Enhancing fairness of pre-trained deep neural networks with scarce data resources," Currently under review, 2023.

Employment History

Aug 2020 – Dec 2023

Aug 2019 – Aug 2020

Apr 2018 – June 2020

Application Developer Pervasive Technology Institute, Bloomington, IN

May 2017 – Aug 2017

Assistant Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN

Software Developer Indiana University School of Optometry, Bloomington, IN

Application Developer Pervasive Technology Institute, Bloomington, IN

Aug 2016 – Dec 2017 **Teaching Assistant** Indiana University Bloomington, Bloomington, IN

Miscellaneous Experience

Awards and Achievements

Intelligent Systems for Sustainable Urban Mobility Travel Expenses
Total: Can\$1,500 from Intelligent Systems for Sustainable Urban Mobility (ISSUM)

Vision: Science to Applications AwardsTotal: Can\$7,500 from Vision: Science to Applications (VISTA), York University

Graduate Student Fellowship

Total: \$39,041 from University Information Technology Services (UITS), Indiana University

Anurag & Aruna Mendhekar Scholarship

Total: \$2,000 from Luddy School of Informatics, Computing, and Engineering, Indiana University Bloomington

Software Development

Purdue University, West Lafayette, IN
SNARKProbe: An Automated Security Analysis Framework for zkSNARK Implementation
(https://github.com/fanym919/snarkprobe)

2019-2020 Indiana University, Bloomignton, IN

DLO Post Processing: Glaucomatous Blind Spots Analysis and Blood Vessel Calibration

System

York University, Toronto, ON
Trans-Plan: An Intelligent Systems for Sustainable Urban Mobility
(https://www.elderlab.yorku.ca/research/systems/)